# 哈喽 大家好
Hi everyone
# 今天我伯爷赶场卖肉特意留了一小块来做这个樱桃肉
Today my uncle kept a piece of pork from the market for some Cherry pork (braised pork)
# 四伯爷你怎么留这么一点安
Uncle, why did you keep so little?
# 留这点儿的（都不错了）别人已经买了我特意割下来的
You should be grateful. This piece was sold and I still managed to cut some off
# 我想到那樱桃出来了拿回来喊二娃整点樱桃肉来吃
It’s cherry season and I thought of asking Erwa to make some braised pork
# 不然一哈都卖了
Otherwise all of it would be sold out quickly
# 是不 是啊
Right, right
# 那我们先把这个肉烧一下
Then let’s grill the pork skin (to remove unpleasant smell)
# 好好
Alright
# 可以了
Done
# 幸好拿的长的钩子小钩子肯定很烫的
Glad we got the long hook. A shorter hook will burn my hand
# 烫得不得了吧 嗯
It’s pretty hot, huh?
# 好了 我们这个肉就烧了之后
Alright, after we burnt the pork skin
# 拿温水或清水把它泡一下
Rinse it with some warm water
# 泡2分钟这个 非常好洗
Soak it for 2 minutes and the burnt parts would be easier to be rinsed off
# 我拿那个碗些来
I’ll bring a bowl for you
# 轻轻的洗掉了
It would come off easily
# 现在我们这个猪皮已经把它洗干净了
Now we’ve already cleaned the skin of the pork
# 这一次我们就做得非常简单
This time we’ll make it simple
# 就直接切
Just slice
# 我们先来切第一刀
Let's make the first cut
# 第一刀的话大概切一厘米（宽）左右
Make the slice about one centimeter thick
# 不把这个肉切断
Don’t cut all the way through
# 切到这个位置
Leave it about here
# 然后再横过来切第二刀
Then turn the meat 90 degrees and make the 2nd cut
# 然后再拉过来切第三刀
Then turn again and cut it
# 跟着转（转着切）呀
Turn and slice?
# 嗯跟着转
Yeah turn and slice
# 然后切第四刀
Then we slice again
# 这样的一块肉就切到这么长
Cut the meat to a strip like this
# 然后我们在翻过来
Then we turn it to the opposite side
# 也是同样的切一厘米左右把皮子留在上面
Slice for every 1cm but remain the skin intact
# 让它连着
To keep the pieces together
# 等会儿夹（着吃）的时候就戳这个就可以了
The chopsticks can pick each piece up later
# 但是前提是要把这个烧耙
As long as we cook it tender enough
# 如果烧得不耙那个皮子戳不断
It needs to be soft enough for the chopsticks to separate them
# 你切得好长一条哦
It’s really long
# 没关系啊
It’s okay
# 就是要它长安
I wanted it to be long
# 好了 现在我们这个已经改好刀了
Alright, now the meat is in proper shape
# 这一串肉就像鞭炮一样
It looks like a bunch of firecrackers
# 是不是 四伯爷 嗯
Right uncle? Yeah
# 像不像火炮 是啊
Like firecrackers? Yeah
# 像噶
Looks alike?
# 嗯 是啊一模一样
Yeah indeed
# 现在我们这样子切好之后直接下锅
After slicing, let’s cook it
# 直接焯下水之后
Parboil it first
# 直接把它稍微爆一下油然后就放其他东西进去烧
Then render the fat out and braise it with other ingredients
# 特别的简单
It’s really straightforward
# 放在这里面
Put it in here first
# 然后准备一点姜片
Slice some ginger
# 再准备一棵大葱
Then some spring onions
# 直接切段就可以
Cut it into segments
# 然后我们这个里面准备了2片香叶
The spices include 2 bay leaves
# 一些这陈皮还有三颗八角
Some dried mandarin peel and three whole star anises
# 然后可以放点山楂呀什么的进去
You can also put some hawthorn in it
# 就增加这个鲜甜味
To make it sweeter and more savory
# 还有冰糖
We also need some white rock sugar
# 搞忘记这个东西了最重要的
Almost forgot the most important stuff
# 然后我们准备一大块
Get a large piece
# 把它敲一下
Hit it
# 这样子敲到处洒起
It will spread everywhere with the way you hit it
# 好了 拍撒之后可以了
Alright, smash it into smaller pieces
# 我去拿一个碗来（装）
Let me get a bowl for it
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水
First we add some water in the wok
# 然后把切好的五花肉下锅焯水
Then parboil the pork
# 中途加半勺料酒去腥
Add some Chinese cooking wine to get rid of the smell
# 大火烧开之后再撇去浮沫
Bring it to a boil and get rid of the scum
# 焯好水之后到出下一步准备炸五花肉
After parboilling, drain off the water and prepare to fry the pork
# 锅烧热之后加入一些宽油
Heat up the wok and add Kuan You (literally “broad oil”)
# 油温烧至5成热再把五花肉下锅炸2分钟
Heat up the oil to about 150°C and deep fry the pork for 2 minutes
# 同学们这样可以去除肥肉中的一些油脂
This way we can remove some fat from the pork
# 略炸之后捞出备用
Take it out after deep frying it
# 热油到出下一步开始准备炒糖色
Pour out the oil. The next step is making the caramelized sugar
# 首先我们直接加入敲碎的冰糖
Put the smashed rock sugar in the wok
# 再加入和冰糖1:1的清水
Add an equal amount of water
# 然后把冰糖熬成糖色
Then boil the sugar to caramelize it
# 糖色炒好之后加入适量的开水继续熬2分钟
After it’s done, add some boiling water to cook for 2 more minutes
# 同学们可别小看这2分钟
These 2 minutes are really important
# 这样可以让糖色不分层断色
This way the color will be evenly distributed on the pork
# 糖色完全融合之后倒出备用
After the caramelized sugar is well mixed, pour it out
# 下一步开始制作
Now let’s cook the pork
# 首先把配好的姜葱和香料下锅小火炒香
First stir fry the ginger, spring onions and spices with low heat until fragrant
# 香料炒香之后加入五花肉翻炒几下
After the spices are fragrant, add in the pork and stir fry
# 然后加入适量的清水
Add some water
# 清水的量最好能烧制40分钟以上
Have enough water that can braise for more than 40 minutes
# 大概需要没过五花肉即可
About the volume to submerge the pork
# 加入适量的糖色大火烧开
Put the caramelized sugar in and bring it to boil
# 大火烧开之后再加入适量的冰糖
When it starts to boil, add some sugar
# 然后转小火烧40分钟
Then lower the heat and braise for a total of 40 minutes
# 中途捡去姜葱和辅料（20分钟后）
After 20 minutes, pick the ginger, spring onions and other ingredients
# 捡去辅料之后加入适量的食用盐调咸味
After picking them out, season with salt
# 调好味之后继续小火烧20分钟
Braise for another 20 minutes
# 同学们这个时候要密切关注锅中的变化
Keep an eye on what's happening in the wok
# 因为此时的糖浆非常容易烧糊
The caramelized sugar gets burnt very easily
# 当汁水变得浓稠之后即可出锅摆盘
When the sauce thickens, it’s ready
# 可以了 四伯爷
It’s ready, uncle
# 呵呵 看到是好看
Ha it looks nice
# 是不 绯红的
Right? Look at the reddish color
# 四伯爷
Uncle
# 来嘛
Come on
# 碗
Here’s the bowl
# 自己戳来吃哦
Help yourself
# 要的呀
Alright
# 自己戳
Pick a piece yourself
# 如果你嫌硬的话可以再烧一会儿的
If the texture is not soft enough, braise longer
# 再拿来烧一会儿
Braise for a little longer
# 大家可以看一下这个
Have a look, guys
# 我尝一下
Let me taste this
# 嗯
Nice
# 咬得动噻 咬得动咬得动
Soft enough? Yeah the texture is good
# 安逸
Nice
# 好干（吃）
Delicious
# 吃 多吃两坨
Have some more
# 看这就没得皮子的
This piece isn't keeping intact with the skin
# 安逸
Nice
# 就是说把这个红烧肉切小块一点
If we slice the pork to smaller pieces
# 烧起红通通的就跟樱桃一样
After cooking, the red color makes it look like cherries
# （樱桃肉的名字）主要是这样子喊出来的
That’s the reason it is also called “Cherry Pork”
# 现在还正是吃樱桃的时候
It is the cherry season now
# 就是吃这个肉的时候
Also the season for this “Red Braised Pork”
# 是 嗯安逸
Yeah. So nice!
# 现在就吃这个 等会儿就吃皮子
Have the meat first and then we’ll move on to the skin
# 嗯好吃 真的好吃
Yeah it’s good. It’s really good
# 这样子整起一个人害怕要吃一斤多肉哦
I’m afraid I’ll have more than 500 grams myself
# 你有没得浪凶得哦
Seriously?
# 试哈看嘛 看我吃得完不嘛
Let me have a try
# 主要这样子吃的话也不腻
It’s not too greasy
# 安逸
Nice
# 你看嘛 我都吃了好多了这一截都是我夹了的
See? I’ve already had a lot. I ate all the meat over this side
# 嗯
Yeah
# 我把这干的这一截夹来吃
I’ll have this piece too
# 如果牙口不好的话可以炖的时间稍微长一些
You can braise it for a little longer if you have dental problems
# 这样放在嘴里一抿就化了的这种
It melts in your mouth
# 我这个只做了40分钟
I only braised it for 40 minutes
# 如果要软一点就可以做一个小时以上
You can go for an hour to make it softer
# 一年十二月每个月你整一回给我吃就可以了
I want to have it once a month
# 这个经常吃要吃腻
You will get tired of it that often
# 一个月吃一回不得多噻
Once a month is not too often
# 一个月两回都不得腻四伯爷
I think twice a month is even good, uncle
# 吃一回嘛就可以了
I’ll be satisfied with once
# 我达到这个愿望就可以了
That’s my wish
# 要的
Alrighty
# 你把肉准备起就是 嘿嘿
As long as you provide the pork hehe
# 拿肉没得问题我随便削一刀下来就够了
That’s perfectly fine. I’ll just cut a piece randomly
# 嗯
Right
# 我干到这一行的未必还这个肉还整它不到吗
I’m a butcher. How come I can't find a piece of pork?
# 这个好吃
This is really nice
# 好 我们这个红烧肉吃完了来吃这个
Alright, let’s have some of these after the pork
# 这个是我们这个本地樱桃
These are the local cherries
# 本地樱桃
Local cherries
# 嗯
Right
# 这个有点酸
It’s a bit sour
# 这个本味都嘛
That’s the original flavor though
# 嗯
Yeah
# 可以还多安逸这个樱桃跟吃胡豆米一样
Nice. These cherries taste like broad beans
# 这个就特别适合吃完有一些有一点肥腻的东西
The cherries are great fit for greasy food
# 然后吃这个酸酸的甜甜的
Sweet and sour
# 特别解腻
Really balances off the grease
# 安逸
Nice
# 嗯 真的很酸
Man it’s pretty sour
# 我吃了几个酸得不得了
I can no longer bear it after a few
# 我还吃得惯
I’m good
# 两颗两颗的吃
Even two of them every mouthful